<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Nikhil Gupta]]></title>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-22T12:28:52+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nikhgupta.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nikhil Gupta]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@nikhgupta.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back with a Bang!]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2013/10/22/back-with-a-bang/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-22T06:21:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2013/10/22/back-with-a-bang</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh, yes! I am, definitely, back &ndash; with a bang! Before, an interpretion is made
on the word, you ought to know about <code>!#</code>: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shebang_(Unix">Shebang</a>.</p>

<p>First, let me talk about <strong>Writing</strong> &ndash; a habit that I have cultivated over time,
and a strong case can be made for the fact that it is one of the rarest
recreational stuff that I do and preach to my friends. It can be really helpful,
and at the same time, can take you to an n-dimensional hyperspace, where you can
imagine nearly anything you want to believe or create. Not only that, for me,
writing is a process to jot down those pesky little thoughts (hundreds of them)
that roam inside my mind like ants near a sugar cube. I, usually, keep
a personal diary where I am able to write these things down, but then, I am
craving for some social interaction (online, to be precise) and maintaining
a steady blog can really help with that.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Anyways, I write here. And, I write rarely as per the reasons stated above. But,
I am thinking to make a switch &ndash; give it a try. I won&rsquo;t be writing anything
personal, but atleast, I will be trying to make a steady attempt at posting once
per day &ndash; on coding, particularly.</p>

<p>Coming back to the <em>bang</em>, anyone who knows will agree that I live in code.
<strong>Shebang</strong> is probably the first thing that crosses my mind when I wake up, and
definitely, the last when I sleep. But, these days, I am leaning towarding
combining the two. That can either be done via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Literate_programming">Literate Programming</a>
(when coding), or otherwise, writing about code (when writing).</p>

<p>In order to accomplish the above goals, I have setup a new blog at the current
address &ndash; with only a few posts from the past. I am using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>,
and yes, I chose it over <a href="http://wordpress.org">WordPress</a>, again.</p>

<p>Reasons for switching are really simple:</p>

<ul>
<li>Comfort of using <a href="http://www.vim.org">Vim</a> or
<a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a> to write my posts. In particular,
<a href="http://orgmode.org">Emacs' Org mode</a> is a godsend for writing your thoughts.
I have been using it since last 2 months or so, and I am pretty confident with
it, now.</li>
<li>Posts are versioned and securely stored inside a Github repository.</li>
<li>Site is served via Github pages, which in turn means, safer hosting. I am
always experimenting with my hosting server, and often time, I am able to blow
it up. Hosting my site on Github ensures that it is free from such
manipulations and always served nicely.</li>
<li>It, just, feels more appropriate. :)</li>
</ul>


<p>So, I used the <a href="https://github.com/shashankmehta/greyshade">GreyShade</a> theme
from <a href="http://shashankmehta.in">Shashank Mehta</a>, a fellow IIT guy (yeah, I have
served my time at IIT Delhi, too :P) and, gave it a simple spin to roll out with
the current version. I must say, he has done a really good work with the
Octopress theme and definitely, deserves a kudos!</p>

<p>Now, the site is all up and running and I, quickly, want to jot down a few tasks
that I am committed for this month:</p>

<ul>
<li>Improve upon the current website design.</li>
<li>Write a post daily on the current website, preferably, about coding in ruby.</li>
<li>Setup org mode in Emacs, so that I can write my blog posts using it.</li>
<li>Create a few basic public APIs:

<ul>
<li>an API that lists words matching a given pattern.</li>
<li>a WhoIs API that also, lists available domains matching a given pattern.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Create a few basic applications using RoR:

<ul>
<li>a domain searching application, somewhat like <a href="http://domai.nr">domai.nr</a></li>
<li>an application that makes it easy to run scripts on servers (have detailed
specifications listed in a separate personal diary)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
