<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Nikhil Gupta]]></title>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-27T16:58:51+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nikhgupta.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nikhil Gupta]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@nikhgupta.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the bizarre events of the last week]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/personal/the-bizarre-events-of-the-last-week/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-26T19:49:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/personal/the-bizarre-events-of-the-last-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong>TL&DR;</strong><br/>
I had a road accident few days back, and I broke my jaw. Doctors put
temporarily braces in my mouth and told me not to speak for a complete month.
Fortunately, I suffered no other injuries, but the doctors also put me on
a liquid diet.</p></blockquote>

<p>Normally, such a post would make into my diary, but considering the interest
generated by my friends and my clients, I preferred to write it all down here.
This post is supposed to provide an overview of the chronological order of the
incidents, and that&rsquo;s the sole purpose of this post.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It was a Thursday evening, and having spent the entire day deducing the perfect
User Interface for some end-users, I surely deserved a few rounds. I went to
a lounge named 100% Rock (or, TC &ndash; which, I heavily despise for the fact that
most of their crowd is comprised of high school students). My best friend was to
meet me over there, as she wanted a confirmation about her current boyfriend.</p>

<blockquote><p>I wonder why?</p>

<blockquote><p>Maybe, she thinks I am a better judge of human personna?
How amusing! :P</p></blockquote></blockquote>

<p>After a few drinks and endless talks, we parted and I reached over to
my bike, which I find absolutely stunning in those street-lamps. I started my
bike and enjoyed the cool breeze in the summer nights. It must be midnight.</p>

<p>A thought puzzled up in my mind, and I called up a close friend to discuss
something. As soon as I hanged up the phone, I had already crashed into an
animal that crossed the road from nowhere. The road was dark black. That animal
was black. I could only make out that the road had no lights, and there was
possibly no way to reach me by simply stating the directions to someone on
phone.</p>

<p>I was bleeding profusely from my mouth. It seemed that my jaw had been
dislocated and I could barely breathe. I had to call someone to get me to
nearest first-aid, but the road was empty and the road was dark. Oh, wow.. We do
not have a 911 emergency number in India. So, somehow, I called up at my house
(which was fortunately nearby), and asked them to come pick me up. Since, I knew
it would be harder for them to find me since I could not give them a pin point
direction, I rode my bike again, and parked it at a place where they can spot
me. That place was around 3 KMs from the initial accident location, and I am not
sure how I made through these 3 KMs, probably foolish, but saved atleast 15
minutes of time which would have been wasted finding my exact location earlier.</p>

<p>Anyways, I was admitted in Emergency and they stitched me up, and asked me to
visit a Plastic Surgeon in the morning. I felt there was no big deal, as the
pain killers have started to kick in by this time, and I could easily speak and
all. I felt it was a normal accident.</p>

<p>So, the next day I went to this doctor, and made him see some of the scans, etc.
and expected him to say something like its a normal thing and that I was okay.
Instead, he said, &ldquo;Your jaw has been fractured. We need to insert metal supports
and probably, wire up your mouth for a month long&rdquo;. That last line killed me.
I don&rsquo;t care if they need to insert metal supports or if my jaw was fractured.
I hate those wire braces, and more than I hate not speaking. I can&rsquo;t can&rsquo;t-speak
for more than 5 minutes.</p>

<p>Anyways, I was admitted for the above, and I asked the doctors to put me in
a public ward instead of a private one. The reason seemed obvious to me. I knew
the injury was quite too much for me, but I also knew it was not a really big
deal, which was confirmed once I had been shifted to a public ward. I saw a guy
with his legs joined to each other with metal support and what not. For the
first time in my life, hospitals did not make me sick, that environment did not
make me leave it, but instead I could find the courage I lacked in the
sufferrings of the persons lying around me. All I had to think was probably,
I was saved, or probably, God was being funnier. He left you to do anything and
everything else you want, just prohibited you from speaking for some unknown
reasons.</p>

<p>Well, they first sealed my mouth as they said &ndash; horizontally and vertically.
I could not make a movement inside my mouth. And, then, they operated me and
inserted some small metal plates for support. I could not feel those plates,
cannot feel them still, but I could feel those wires around my mouth, and I was
immediately reminded of the Tom Hardy character (Bane) from the Dark Knight
rises &ndash; the only difference being the metal is all inside my mouth :)</p>

<p>Anyways, I am back home, and I am still pondering on how to best spend this next
one month, but I am sure things could have gone a lot worse than that, but
I have been saved.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The overdue silence]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/personal/diary/the-overdue-silence/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-01T13:18:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/personal/diary/the-overdue-silence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>It&rsquo;s wonderful. This new year. The <code>2014</code>.<br/>
Everything seems different &ndash; not in their appearance or behaviour or
properties, but it feels like things have a new soul, or like an invisible
painting has been performed on them to give them a more living feeling.</p></blockquote>

<p>I know. I know. New year, sometimes, have such an effect on individuals, and
I am no different. I am a person who appreciates art, and the new year just
happens to bring so much of it. So, let me first wish a new year to you and to
me, with a wish that this year will give us the ever-elusive satisfaction every
one wants in their life, that this year will bring us closer to our dreams &ndash; the
precious!</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Apology</h2>

<p>Via this blog post, I wanted to put an excuse to my blog for not being able to
post for the last two months, and I am still wondering on one. All I can say is
that:</p>

<blockquote><p>We, the mere humans, are lazy.<br/>
We, the mere humans, can never stick to our promises, no matter how special.</p></blockquote>

<p>To be honest, I got involved with a ruby gem that tried to convert text markup
from one language to another, e.g. from <a href="markdown">Markdown</a> to
<a href="textile">Textile</a> markup, or maybe from <a href="org-mode">Org Mode</a> to
<a href="markdown">Markdown</a>, and so on. Oh, and not only that, I was in the process of
picking up a partner for a few startups I had in my mind, and was building up on
them.</p>

<p>Later, when I was about missing my newly-refreshed blog, things in my
personal life took some turn &ndash; my dad suffered from heart strokes &ndash; two of them
&ndash; in a matter of days. Life sucks for such things.</p>

<p>Moreover, I am really fighting with myself to put an end to my 9-5 job. I have
been wanting to end it since an year, now, and finally, I have decided to do
this. Yeah, I went over this decision, slept over it and what not. A 9-5
government job that has no relation to what I love, what I am passionate about
simply does not make any sense to me or to anyone who knows my affair with
programming and computers, anymore.</p>

<p>Having settled the reasons, all I can say is that I plan on posting regularly,
though I won&rsquo;t make a promise, but I will post when possible.</p>

<h2>Resolutions</h2>

<p>I hate resolutions. They bind me for the things I do not want to do. Now, you
would ask:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Why only things that you do not want to do?</strong></p>

<blockquote><p><em>Because, if I really wanted to do something, I won&rsquo;t wait for the new year to
happen.</em></p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Alright, but even then, resolutions are good, right?</strong></p>

<blockquote><p><em>No! They are evil. They tell me to do something against my freewill. And,
hence, I already know, I won&rsquo;t listen to them after sometime, anyways.</em></p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Okay, so you don&rsquo;t plan on changing yourself, for the good?</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>Who said, I don&rsquo;t want to do that. You must first tell me what&rsquo;s wrong with
me, for this conversation to work out.</p></blockquote></blockquote>

<h2>The First Month</h2>

<p>Oh, yes, I have a few simple plans for this month, which include:</p>

<ul>
<li>posting a timeline of the major events from my life on this blog.</li>
<li>start work on one of the startup ideas I had in my mind.</li>
<li>resign from my 9-5 job and leave the government to work on its own.</li>
<li>pack up and go live in a place with a better climate by the end of the month.</li>
<li>photography visits nearly every week</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[managing your scripts should not be that hard]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/personal/code/managing-your-scripts-should-not-be-that-hard/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-23T01:46:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/personal/code/managing-your-scripts-should-not-be-that-hard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am, often, found creating simple scripts to automate one or the other part of
my life. Most of the times, I would use a combination of project managers, task
managers, automation tools, and so on to do the tedious work for me. But, at the
other times, it is simply so much more easier to give my inner geek a kick in
the butt and start writing some code which will explicitely be used by me to
handle such one off tasks.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Problem</h2>

<p>But, here comes the irony, no matter what I try, I end up either misplacing
these little snippets of code, or otherwise it becomes so much tedious to
collect and keep them in an organized manner. Not to mention, the really
annoying part of creating aliases to these nice snippets and then, forgetting
what aliases you, currently, have. Oh, did I mention, I have to keep them online
in a Git repository, so that they are always versioned and sharing them is easy?
And, what if I am booting a new server or working on some other one-time
machine, it would kill me to do a clone of this repository, and then run them
via their full paths, and what if the script does not work on this new machine,
or what if I had to leave meanwhile?</p>

<p>Let me have a quick answer: it is not the 1990s, where the above issues
classified as a GNU license, and nor it is the 2000&rsquo;s, when I did not know how
to create an app dedicated for my own purposes.</p>

<h2>The Solution</h2>

<p>The solution? It&rsquo;s easy. Search for an existing solution or roll out our own.
Unfortunately, I was unable to find an existing solution (or, atleast, I will
pretend the same), and therefore will be rolling out my own, with the following
features:</p>

<ul>
<li>Has a client side gem that can be used to list a user&rsquo;s scripts, and allow him
to copy them in a folder on his machine, and assign aliases to these scripts
on the go.</li>
<li>The gem should be able to search for scripts based on some keywords.</li>
<li>User should be able to have CRUD rights over their scripts. They should be
able to share these scripts, as well as export them. They should be able to
reference another script inside the script they are creating.</li>
<li>All the scripts would be created use Github Gists, and hence, be versioned.</li>
<li>The application should provide an interface to write (and, probably, test) the
scripts on the server, itself. Provide a dedicated backend to the user?</li>
<li>The users should be able to run the scripts on their server via the app
interface, once they have the SSH authentication established? This is not as
straight-forward, since the app server will be the one connecting to the
user&rsquo;s server and hence, it is not safe.</li>
<li>Scripts should have a unique programming structure, which identifies their
requirements and alike, and notifies the user about the same.</li>
<li>Logging should be done on cloud for output of the scripts.</li>
<li>Scripts should be marked as safe based on their MD5 hash, kinda like thor
does for its installed scripts.</li>
<li>Scripts should be intelligent in telling the user when the runtime is not
available, e.g. the user tries to run a ruby script on a server with no-ruby
installed.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back with a Bang!]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/personal/back-with-a-bang/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-22T06:21:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/personal/back-with-a-bang</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh, yes! I am, definitely, back &ndash; with a bang! Before, an interpretion is made
on the word, you ought to know about <code>!#</code>: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shebang_(Unix">Shebang</a>.</p>

<p>First, let me talk about <strong>Writing</strong> &ndash; a habit that I have cultivated over time,
and a strong case can be made for the fact that it is one of the rarest
recreational stuff that I do and preach to my friends. It can be really helpful,
and at the same time, can take you to an n-dimensional hyperspace, where you can
imagine nearly anything you want to believe or create. Not only that, for me,
writing is a process to jot down those pesky little thoughts (hundreds of them)
that roam inside my mind like ants near a sugar cube. I, usually, keep
a personal diary where I am able to write these things down, but then, I am
craving for some social interaction (online, to be precise) and maintaining
a steady blog can really help with that.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Anyways, I write here. And, I write rarely as per the reasons stated above. But,
I am thinking to make a switch &ndash; give it a try. I won&rsquo;t be writing anything
personal, but atleast, I will be trying to make a steady attempt at posting once
per day &ndash; on coding, particularly.</p>

<p>Coming back to the <em>bang</em>, anyone who knows will agree that I live in code.
<strong>Shebang</strong> is probably the first thing that crosses my mind when I wake up, and
definitely, the last when I sleep. But, these days, I am leaning towarding
combining the two. That can either be done via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Literate_programming">Literate Programming</a>
(when coding), or otherwise, writing about code (when writing).</p>

<p>In order to accomplish the above goals, I have setup a new blog at the current
address &ndash; with only a few posts from the past. I am using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>,
and yes, I chose it over <a href="http://wordpress.org">WordPress</a>, again.</p>

<p>Reasons for switching are really simple:</p>

<ul>
<li>Comfort of using <a href="http://www.vim.org">Vim</a> or
<a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a> to write my posts. In particular,
<a href="http://orgmode.org">Emacs' Org mode</a> is a godsend for writing your thoughts.
I have been using it since last 2 months or so, and I am pretty confident with
it, now.</li>
<li>Posts are versioned and securely stored inside a Github repository.</li>
<li>Site is served via Github pages, which in turn means, safer hosting. I am
always experimenting with my hosting server, and often time, I am able to blow
it up. Hosting my site on Github ensures that it is free from such
manipulations and always served nicely.</li>
<li>It, just, feels more appropriate. :)</li>
</ul>


<p>So, I used the <a href="https://github.com/shashankmehta/greyshade">GreyShade</a> theme
from <a href="http://shashankmehta.in">Shashank Mehta</a>, a fellow IIT guy (yeah, I have
served my time at IIT Delhi, too :P) and, gave it a simple spin to roll out with
the current version. I must say, he has done a really good work with the
Octopress theme and definitely, deserves a kudos!</p>

<p>Now, the site is all up and running and I, quickly, want to jot down a few tasks
that I am committed for this month:</p>

<ul>
<li>Migrate old posts from various sources to the current blog.</li>
<li>Redirect old blog&rsquo;s links to the current blog.</li>
<li>Improve upon the current website design.

<ul>
<li>The header hover should occur when hovering over the picture and not when
hovering over the header, itself. This is a bit difficult in pure CSS3,
since that defies the <code>cascading</code> rule of CSS, and instead, tries to modify
the parent from the child.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Write a post daily on the current website, preferably, about coding in ruby.</li>
<li>Setup org mode in Emacs, so that I can write my blog posts using it.</li>
<li>Create a few basic public APIs:

<ul>
<li>an API that lists words matching a given pattern.</li>
<li>a WhoIs API that also, lists available domains matching a given pattern.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Create a few basic applications using RoR:

<ul>
<li>a domain searching application, somewhat like <a href="http://domai.nr">domai.nr</a></li>
<li>an application that makes it easy to run scripts on servers (have detailed
specifications listed in a separate personal diary)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
