<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: code | Nikhil Gupta]]></title>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/categories/code/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-21T12:22:46+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nikhgupta.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nikhil Gupta]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@nikhgupta.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim as PHP IDE: Ctags, and Code Browsing]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/04/01/using-vim-php-ide-exuberant-ctags-code-browsing/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/04/01/using-vim-php-ide-exuberant-ctags-code-browsing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, past few weeks, I have been really fascinated with the all powerful Vim.
And, I often wonder why: I took so much time switching to it? Probably, the
steep learning curve! It has to be.</p>

<p>Anyways, so I have really really progressed with Vim this time, as compared to
my earlier trials. I am quite efficient with Vim now &ndash; even writing this blog
post on it. I know how to move quickly, make efficient uses of search and
replace, using Vim scripts etc. I have really really found plugins like
Gundo, Fugitive, Tagbar, Syntastic, Snipmate, NerdTree, and Powerline to be
useful and not to mention plugins like Vim-Rails which make my day-to-day
tasks easier with a particular language. Oh, and did I mention the incredible
<code>!</code> and <code>@</code> operators? They just rock!</p>

<p>But, well. This post is about using Ctags with Vim to make Vim feel more like
an IDE and readily use Source Code Browsing within frameworks, large code
projects, etc. Here, in this post, I have specified my configuration/process
for using Ctags with MacVim for a CakePHP based project.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>The Process</h3>

<p>Well, I would try to create my Ctags on the fly, using Git hooks. This lets me
simply checkout, merge or commit to a branch and my tags would be generated
for the code in question. Moreover, these Ctags generated files are stored
inside <code>.git</code> directory, which keeps our repositories clean (no need to add
a file to <code>.gitignore</code>). Also, I would prefer a centralized place where I can
manage any script I use to create these Ctags, and hence, if after about an
year I think I need a change in the way script is working, or if say I want to
add support for or remove support for a language, I should be able to do it
from a single place and affect all my git repositories using these Ctags
hooks.</p>

<p>For this to work, i.e. for Vim to pick up our Ctags (that will be created in
<code>.git/tags</code> file) we need to have <code>Fugitive</code> installed (which I will really
really recommend anyways). This will make Vim look for Ctags in a <code>.git/tags</code>
and <code>.git/&lt;lang&gt;.tags</code> file in our repository, irrespective of the current
working directory.</p>

<p>Let   s set up a default set of hooks that Git will use as a template when
creating or cloning a repository (requires Git 1.7.1 or newer):</p>

<p><code>bash
git config --global init.templatedir '~/.git_template'
mkdir -p ~/.git_template/hooks
</code></p>

<p>I, usually, put all my Git related stuff in <code>~/Code/__dotfiles/git/</code> and
hence, the above template directory lands up as
<code>~/Code/__dotfiles/git/template/</code> with all the hooks, in my
<a href="http://github.com/nikhgupta/dotfiles">.dotfiles</a> repository.</p>

<p>Now onto the first hook, which isn&rsquo;t actually a hook at all, but rather
a script the other hooks will call. Place in <code>~/.git_template/hooks/ctags</code> and
mark as executable:</p>

<p>``` bash</p>

<h1>!/bin/sh</h1>

<p>rm -f .git/tags ctags &mdash;tag-relative -Rf.git/tags \
  &mdash;exclude=.git &mdash;languages=-javascript,sql
```</p>

<p>Although, make sure that the <code>ctags</code> version is the GNU one, and the above
script runs without showing any errors. If installing via <code>Homebrew</code> make sure
that the <code>which ctags</code> command shows the correct <code>ctags</code> executable path.</p>

<p>Making this a separate script makes it easy to invoke <code>.git/hooks/ctags</code> for
a one-off re-index (or <code>git config --global alias.ctags '!.git/hooks/ctags'</code>,
then <code>git ctags</code>), as well as easy to edit for that special case repository
that needs a different set of options to ctags. For example, I might want to
re-enable indexing for JavaScript or SQL files, which I&rsquo;ve disabled here
because I&rsquo;ve found both to be of limited value and noisy in the warning
department.  And, in these edge cases, all I need is to modify the
corresponding <code>.git/hooks/ctags</code> script in that git repository. Neat and
clean.</p>

<p>We still need to create the actual hooks that the Git will copy to all
repositories that are (re)initialized using the <code>git init</code> command.  All the
files in the <code>~/.git_template/hooks</code> folder needs to be marked as executables.
You should use the following content for: <code>post-commit</code>, <code>post-merge</code>, and
<code>post-checkout</code> hooks (which simply calls the <code>ctags</code> hook, we create above):</p>

<p>``` bash</p>

<h1>!/bin/sh</h1>

<p>.git/hooks/ctags >/dev/null 2>&amp;1 &amp;
```</p>

<p>Additionally, if you feel tags should also be generated on using <code>git rebase</code>,
add the following code to <code>post-rewrite</code> hook:</p>

<p>``` bash</p>

<h1>!/bin/sh</h1>

<p>case &ldquo;$1&rdquo; in
  rebase) exec .git/hooks/post-merge ;;
esac
```</p>

<p>Once, the above is done, all we need to do is to issue a <code>git init</code> command to
create Ctags for an already existing repository. All new git repositories will
automatically include these hooks and hence, will create the Ctags file on the
fly. Pure Automation. ;)</p>

<h3>Global Projects</h3>

<p>There are some projects that I always want available for source code browsing
like the Rails source code itself. For such projects, I would generally run
a one-off shell script that does this work for me, and store the generated
tags file in a directory such as <code>~/.tags/</code> with a suitable name. O'course it
does not make sense to version this directory.</p>

<p>``` bash</p>

<h1>!/usr/bin/env sh</h1>

<p>RubyVersion=&ldquo;1.9.3-p194&rdquo;
LaravelPath=&ldquo;${HOME}/Code/projects/lab/laravel&rdquo;</p>

<p>mkdir -p &ldquo;${HOME}/.ctags&rdquo;</p>

<h1>RVM: Ruby version 1.9.3-p194</h1>

<p>if [ -n &ldquo;${RubyVersion}&rdquo; ]; then
  mkdir -p &ldquo;${HOME}/.ctags/ruby/${RubyVersion}&rdquo;
  TAG_FILE=&ldquo;${HOME}/.ctags/ruby/${RubyVersion}/tags&rdquo;
  rm -f &ldquo;${TAG_FILE}&rdquo;
  for rubydir in <code>find "${HOME}/.rvm/gems" -type d -depth 1 -iname "*${RubyVersion}*"</code>; do</p>

<pre><code>if [ -d "${rubydir}/gems" ]; then
  echo "Looking inside: ${rubydir}/gems"
  ctags --recurse --tag-relative \
    --languages=-javascript,sql \
    --exclude=.git \
    --sort=yes --append \
    -f "${TAG_FILE}" \
    $rubydir/gems/*
fi
</code></pre>

<p>  done
  echo
  echo &ldquo;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash; generated ctags for: ${RubyVersion} &mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&rdquo;
  cat &ldquo;${TAG_FILE}&rdquo; | wc
  echo &ldquo;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&ndash;&rdquo;
  echo
fi</p>

<h1>Laravel</h1>

<p>if [ -n &ldquo;${LaravelPath}&rdquo; -a -d &ldquo;${LaravelPath}&rdquo; ]; then
  mkdir -p &ldquo;${HOME}/.ctags/php/laravel&rdquo;
  TAG_FILE=&ldquo;${HOME}/.ctags/php/laravel/tags&rdquo;
  rm -f &ldquo;${TAG_FILE}&rdquo;
  echo &ldquo;Looking inside: ${LaravelPath}&rdquo;
  ctags &mdash;recurse &mdash;tag-relative \</p>

<pre><code>--languages=-javascript,sql \
--exclude=.git \
--sort=yes --append \
--PHP-kinds=+cf \
--regex-PHP='/abstract class ([^ ]*)/\1/c/' \
--regex-PHP='/interface ([^ ]*)/\1/c/' \
--regex-PHP='/(public |static |abstract |protected |private )+function ([^ (]*)/\2/f/' \
-f "${TAG_FILE}" \
$LaravelPath
</code></pre>

<p>  echo
  echo &ldquo;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash; generated ctags for: Laravel &mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&ndash;&rdquo;
  cat &ldquo;${TAG_FILE}&rdquo; | wc
  echo &ldquo;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&ndash;&rdquo;
  echo
fi
```</p>

<p>Finally, I set the following inside my <code>~/.vimrc</code> file:</p>

<p><code>vim
set tags=./tags;/
augroup TagFileType
  autocmd!
  autocmd FileType * setl tags&lt;
  autocmd FileType * exe 'setl tags+=~/.ctags/' . &amp;filetype . '/*/tags'
augroup END
</code></p>

<p>This basically tells vim to only load ctags for the current filetype, i.e. for
a <code>ruby</code> buffer, vim will load all ctags files inside <code>~/.ctags/ruby</code>
directory, and no ctags file inside <code>~/.ctags/php</code></p>

<h3>Epilogue</h3>

<p>(Now, that I have completed writing the post and I read it again, it seems
that this post feels like a rewrite <a href="http://tbaggery.com/2011/08/08/effortless-ctags-with-git.html">a post by tPope</a>. Well,
I was originally thinking of a different way to create these Ctags, but as
I went deeper and deeper, I realized that what
<a href="https://github.com/tpope">tPope</a> describes is so natural and easy, that
I have to ditch whatever it is &ndash; what I was doing now. And, do not forget,
I am less than a month old with Vim and I am talking Ctags with Vim.  I am
allowed to reherse my steps :P )</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim: Gundo and Tabular plugins]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/03/28/vim-awesomeness-gundo-and-tabular-plugins/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/03/28/vim-awesomeness-gundo-and-tabular-plugins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I switched to MacVim in order to give VIM another shot. Since, then,
Vim has kept on amazing me with its feature set.</p>

<p>Learning from Vimcasts.org, I get to know the Gundo and Tabular plugins. This
post is a short excerpt of what they do and how they help me in my day to day
editing.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Gundo</h3>

<p>Traditional editors have a concept of undo-redo which is fairly simple &ndash; you
can do something &ndash; undo it and redo it, i.e. you can traverse on path <code>ABEFG</code></p>

<p>VIM allows me to traverse the changes in a chronological manner, as well. That
is to say, I can even go to edits not in the same timeline, i.e. I am able to
traverse <code>ABCDEFG</code> as they happened.</p>

<p>``` text</p>

<pre><code>      / `---------- C ---- D
</code></pre>

<p>A&mdash;&ndash; B &mdash; |</p>

<pre><code>      \,----------------------- E ----- F ------- G
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>We can use the <code>:earlier Nm</code> command to go back a few minutes (and even
seconds, hours, days). We can use <code>:GundoToggle</code> to view a quick Ascii tree of
our changes and compare the two edits in the vim timeline for undos</p>

<h3>Tabular</h3>

<p>I can simply align my code using <code>:Tabularize /{pattern}</code>. For example, to
align assignments I can use something like <code>:Tab /=</code> and, if I prefer to keep
the spaces attached to the code on the left, I can use something like <code>:Tab
/=\zs</code> The effects will be as below:</p>

<p>``` ruby</p>

<h1>no tabularize</h1>

<p>a = 1322
abc = 1323
abcde = 1324</p>

<h1>:Tab /=</h1>

<p>a     = 1322
abc   = 1323
abcde = 1324</p>

<h1>:Tab /=\zs</h1>

<p>a =     1322
abc =   1323
abcde = 1324
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[5minutes.to Beta Video]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/03/28/5minutes-to-beta-video/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/03/28/5minutes-to-beta-video</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I have been involved with the <a href="http://5minutes.to/">5minutes.to</a>
application. This application helps you get up and ready with your next website
in 5 minutes or less including email addresses, templates and what not.</p>

<p>In this post, I have posted an introductory video we made for
<a href="http://beta.5minutes.to/">5minutes.to</a>, and by all means we love it :)</p>

<!-- more -->




<p><iframe
src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/39292344?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0"
frameborder="0" width="100%" height="500px"></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrapping my Rails application]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/03/20/bootstrapping-my-rails-application/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/03/20/bootstrapping-my-rails-application</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post details my starting steps with a new <a href="http://rubyonrails.org">Rails</a>
project, and is only kept here to remind me of various tasks that I,
generally, like to do at this time. Many of these steps might be redundant or
even, obsolete by the time you lay yours eyes on this post :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<h5>Install Rails</h5>

<p><code>bash
rails new my_app -T -d mysql -j jquery
</code></p>

<h5>Initialize a git repository</h5>

<p><code>bash
cd my_app
git flow init -d # initialize git work-flow
git add .
git commit -am "Installed Rails"
git flow feature start prepare_base
</code></p>

<h5>Create a RVM configuration file</h5>

<p><code>bash
rvm use 1.9.3@rails --rvmrc
</code></p>

<h5>Add some starting gems to Gemfile</h5>

<p>``` ruby
gem &lsquo;haml&rsquo;</p>

<h1>gem &lsquo;kaminari&rsquo;</h1>

<h1>gem &lsquo;devise&rsquo;</h1>

<h1>gem &lsquo;capistrano&rsquo;</h1>

<h1>gem &lsquo;unicorn&rsquo;</h1>

<p>group :test, :development do
  gem &lsquo;turn&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;haml-rails&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;rspec-rails&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;cucumber-rails&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;factory_girl_rails&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;capybara&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;capybara-webkit&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;database_cleaner&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;guard-rspec&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;guard-cucumber&rsquo;
  # gem &lsquo;guard-unicorn&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;ruby_gntp&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;minitest&rsquo;
  gem &lsquo;launchy&rsquo;
end
```</p>

<h5>Run Bundle Install</h5>

<p><code>bash
bundle install
</code></p>

<h5>Add database settings in config/database.yml</h5>

<p><code>bash
rake db:create:all
</code></p>

<h5>Change Home Page</h5>

<p>``` bash
rails generate controller home index
rm -rf public/index.html
find . -type f -iname &ldquo;*.erb&rdquo; -delete # remove all erb files since we are using haml</p>

<h1>add &lsquo;root :to => &ldquo;Home#index&rdquo;&rsquo; in config/routes.rb</h1>

<p>```</p>

<h5>Lets, make some generations, huh.</h5>

<p><code>bash
rails generate rspec:install
rails generate cucumber:install --capybara
guard init rspec &amp;&amp; guard init cucumber
</code></p>

<h5>Make some changes to the <code>features/support/env.rb</code> file:</h5>

<p><code>ruby
require 'cucumber/rails'
require 'capybara/rails'
require 'capybara/cucumber'
require 'capybara/session'
require "factory_girl/step_definitions"
Capybara.default_selector  = :css
Capybara.javascript_driver = :webkit
ActionController::Base.allow_rescue = false
DatabaseCleaner.strategy = :transaction
Cucumber::Rails::Database.javascript_strategy = :truncation
</code></p>

<h5>Lets, add some Cucumber Tests (<code>features/test.feature</code> file):</h5>

<p>``` ruby
Feature: Testing Configuration
  In order to have a base for my new application
  As a developer
  I want to test the configuration settings for this application</p>

<p>  Scenario: Test Home Page</p>

<pre><code>Given I am on the home page
Then  I should see "Home#index"
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<h5>And, the corresponding steps in <code>features/step_definitions/test_steps.rb</code> file:</h5>

<p>``` ruby
Given /^I am on the home page$/ do
  visit &ldquo;/&rdquo;
end</p>

<p>Then /^I should see &ldquo;([^&rdquo;]*)&ldquo;$/ do |text|
  page.should have_content text
end
```</p>

<h5>Open a iTerm2 tab each for the following processes:</h5>

<p>``` bash</p>

<h1>default tab</h1>

<p>guard
tail -fn0 log/test.log
rails console
tail -fn0 log/development.log
rails server
```</p>

<h5>Merge our feature into development</h5>

<p><code>bash
git commit -am "finished with preparing base"
git flow feature finish prepare_base
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started with Ruby and Rails..]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/03/19/thoughts-getting-started-with-ruby-rails/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/blog/2012/03/19/thoughts-getting-started-with-ruby-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so past an year I have been trying to switch into RubyOnRails for
various reasons &ndash; and yes, they are numerous. I wanted to work less with the
<em>how-tos</em> and instead, wanna work more with <em>what-i-want-next</em> when I develop
applications for myself. I wanted to make use of those gorgeous little gems
that will fit in so nicely with my Ruby code &ndash; I wanted to develop business
logic instead of behavior (think devise, paperclip, clearance, and so on) and
then, I, also, wanted to make use of some of the awesome assistants the rail
community has for their everyday tasks (think capistrano, cucumber, and so
on).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Now, I do understand that the language (or I should say Syntax) is easy to
learn and gorgeously, so.</p>

<p>``` php</p>

<h1>Think PHP:</h1>

<p>if (!empty($my_variable)) do_this();
```</p>

<p>``` ruby</p>

<h1>v/s Ruby:</h1>

<p>do_this if my_variable
```</p>

<p>But, then again, learning RubyOnRails has been a tough job. Primarily, due to
the steep learning curve on <em>how-to-get-started-with-ruby-on-rails</em> frontier.</p>

<p>Fortunately, for me, I have been a <code>shell</code> guy &ndash; I, absolutely, adore shell
and rely on it for much of the repetitive tasks, everyday &ndash; kinda to the
extent that, iTerm.app is the most frequently used application on my Mac, just
like every other developer, who understands the sheer power shell puts in our
hand ;) (Not to mention, <code>git</code> is involved in almost all my projects)</p>

<p>So, I went on and installed RVM and loaded it with Rubies and Gems and what
not, and I have been using this setup from quite a long time &ndash; just not enough
to actually start building some awesome application.</p>

<p>This was partly due to the fact that, whenever I needed to make some
application for a client, I would go in and start building it with CakePHP
rather. Probably, the simple reason being I wanted to get on with creating the
application, instead of learning a framework which will create the
application, afterwards. I did not <em>really</em> wanted to invest the time into
RubyOnRails.</p>

<p>But, alas! we are humans &ndash; and, that makes us unsatisfied with whatever little
satisfaction, we might have, by chance. And, I wanted to dwell inside
RubyOnRails world, yet, again. But, this time, I really wanted to go all out
and give it a good fight and either win or lose, but have an outcome at once.</p>

<p>I know, most of us would never go in the step-by-step-of-learnings-steps and
jump to things we don&rsquo;t quite understand &ndash; which is nice, but may often, force
you to give up on things &ndash; which is what used to happen with me. So, this
time, I decided to go slow &ndash; learnings things one step at a time &ndash; and follow
screencasts and tutorials, with all my heart.</p>

<p>Oh, and did I tell you? It was just not enough! I wanted to know if I can use
Vim to be more productive? And, hence I got myself a shiny new MacVim.app to
learn along with (and, I must say its been around 3 weeks and I am more than
happy with what I can do with Vim).</p>

<p>Well, coming back to RubyOnRails, I started with the famous <code>_why</code> tutorial at:
tryruby.org and man! that definitely, did help me a lot (as an example,
earlier I was never aware why some methods had an exclamation in ruby at the
end). So, the first step would be to <em>really</em> know things work in Ruby. And,
TryRuby.org helps with that when you are starting out in Ruby.</p>

<p>Next, I started watching a few screencasts on getting started with RubyOnRails
(note that, I wanted to learn things from the basic &ndash; just so that, I am sure
I have my basics all covered up &ndash; also, note that I have already gone through:
<a href="http://ruby.railstutorial.org/ruby-on-rails-tutorial-book">Michael Hartl&rsquo;s awesome RubyOnRails
book</a>), and
finally, I was really inspired by <a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/ruby/the-intro-to-rails-screencast-i-wish-i-had/">this particular
tutorial</a>
which really explained things a lot, and not to mention the <a href="http://railsforzombies.org">Rails for
Zombies</a> session.</p>

<p>Within a short time, I was up and running with an application I could use to
tweak and learn all-things-rails! However, this is not simply what I wanted.
I wanted to learn new ways &ndash; the tools &ndash; wanted to learn BDD, easy
deployments, and things alike.</p>

<p>So, I next started learning how to use capybara for my BDD needs. BDD is
awesome &ndash; since I can simply write what I wanted and every time I could just
look up what test is failing and write the code for it &ndash; it keeps me on track
with what needs to be done next, and while doing so definitely, takes away the
pain associated with manually testing the application. I guess, the Rails
Introduction tutorial I mentioned above, also, deals with setting up Capybara
with RSpec for testing purposes.</p>

<p>Soon, I found out using Cucumber will further help me be more expressive, and
concise while being forgiving on my clients. So, I started finding out how to
integrate Capybara with Cucumber and <a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/ruby/ruby-for-newbies-testing-web-apps-with-capybara-and-cucumber/">this
screencast</a>
really helped me along with Google searches.</p>

<p>So, now I had Cucumber working along with Capybara, but yet I have always
loved the work done by <a href="http://thoughtbot.com/community/">ThoughtBot Studio</a>
and wanted to utilize Factory Girl in my tests &ndash; so, I started searching and
I guess <a href="http://collectiveidea.com/blog/archives/2010/09/09/practical-cucumber-factory-girl-steps/">this is the
post</a>
that really helped me with getting Factory Girl fixtures to work with my
Cucumber features.</p>

<p>At the end, I would say:</p>

<blockquote><p>I am very new to RubyOnRails world, and wanted to simply pen down my
thoughts about this awesome community at around 6 AM while I am all
exhausted. I would keep updating this post with my thoughts on how I am
learning things in the RubyOnRails world.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
