<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: code | Nikhil Gupta]]></title>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/categories/code/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-07T04:22:09+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nikhgupta.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nikhil Gupta]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@nikhgupta.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[serving legacy php applications using Apache alongside Pow]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/serving-legacy-php-applications-using-apache-alongside-pow/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-03T06:49:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/serving-legacy-php-applications-using-apache-alongside-pow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have started using <a href="http://pow.cx">Pow</a> lately, which I have avoided for
a long time, without any explicit reasoning. Now that I have actually tried it,
I can definitely say that using Pow is really a breeze, and is really powerful
at the same time. Before this, I used to run Phusion Passenger for my needs, and
while that was a lot more powerful, it was a lot more fuss for my naive needs.</p>

<p>Now, Pow is really great for Rack based applications, but does not work well
enough with other applications, e.g. the ones using PHP. What makes it worse is
that the default Pow configuration takes over the port 80, and thereby, my
Apache server will never be hit. Great.</p>

<p>I, quickly, googled some stuff and found a way to make Apache and Pow play
nicely with each other, and at the same time remove the need for <code>dnsmasq</code>,
which I am, currently, using to resolve arbitrary top-level domains. This post
contains my notes on this topic.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Uninstall Pow</h2>

<p>The first step we need to perform is to uninstall Pow, if it is already
installed. That way, we make sure that nothing interferes with our setup.</p>

<p><code>bash
curl get.pow.cx/uninstall.sh | sh
</code></p>

<h2>Add Configuration for Pow</h2>

<p>We will tell Pow to use the port 3100, instead of taking over port 80, and let
the poor Apache be. Furthermore, I will tell Pow to resolve a number of TLDs to
<code>127.0.0.1</code>.</p>

<p><code>bash
echo 'export POW_DST_PORT=88' &gt;&gt; ~/.powconfig
echo 'export POW_DOMAINS=dev,pow,lab,test' &gt;&gt; ~/.powconfig
</code></p>

<p>From the above list of TLDs, we want <code>dev</code>, and <code>pow</code> to serve applications
using Pow, while <code>lab</code> and <code>test</code> will be serving Apache based applications
using VirtualHost directives.</p>

<h2>Adding Apache VirtualHosts</h2>

<p>First, we will tell Apache to pass any requests for <code>dev</code>, and <code>pow</code> TLDs to
Pow using reverse proxy:</p>

<p>```apache
<VirtualHost *:80></p>

<pre><code>ServerName pow
ServerAlias *.dev *.pow *.xip.io

ProxyPass / http://localhost:20559/
ProxyPassReverse / http://localhost:20559/
ProxyPreserveHost On
</code></pre>

<p></VirtualHost>
```</p>

<p>Having done that, we tell Apache to serve up the remaining TLDs from
a particular directory:</p>

<p>```apache
<VirtualHost *:80></p>

<pre><code>ServerName lab
ServerAlias *.lab *.test
VirtualDocumentRoot "/Users/nikhgupta/Code/legacy-apps/%1"
</code></pre>

<p></VirtualHost>
```</p>

<p>Now, make sure that the above directives are being served up by Apache by
including them in your <code>httpd.conf</code> somewhere, somehow.</p>

<h2>Restart Apache</h2>

<p>Apache will use the above VirtualHost directives upon restart/reload:</p>

<p><code>bash
sudo apachectl restart
</code></p>

<h2>Install Pow</h2>

<p>All that remains is to install Pow:</p>

<p><code>bash
curl get.pow.cx | sh
</code></p>

<h2>Install Powder</h2>

<p>Oh, yes, this is my favorite. Simply, install Powder to further simplify your
life.</p>

<p><code>bash
gem install powder
</code></p>

<p><em>Ecstatic</em> :)</p>

<h2>Results?</h2>

<p>For starters, I can serve up any rack based application by simply running
<code>powder list</code> in that directory, and then access it using <code>appname.dev</code> or
<code>appname.pow</code>. And, this also works for static websites as well e.g.
<a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> (note that, this requires that the current
directory has a <code>public</code> sub directory which contains an <code>index.html</code> file.)</p>

<p>Moreover, my old Apache configurations run without any implications. And,
therefore, I can keep on working on applications that are served using PHP.</p>

<p>Effectively, I can run a ruby/rails based application in a single step by
running <code>powder link</code>, and a php application in zero steps by simply placing it
at the correct location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[wrapping long lines in ruby for display in source files]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/wrapping-long-lines-in-ruby-for-display-in-source-files/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T02:42:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/wrapping-long-lines-in-ruby-for-display-in-source-files</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While working on a gem, I needed to generate ruby classes on the fly. Yeah,
I know this should never be the case, unless I needed around 600+ classes (I was
converting schema.org schemas to ruby classes).</p>

<p>Now, this required me to add descriptive text inside these classes, but the text
was very long and I hated how the text overflowed the screen. I use vim, which
promptly highlights the 80-char column marker on my source files, and I wanted
this text to stick to that. Effectively, I wanted something like the following:</p>

<p>```ruby
module MyModule
  class MyClass</p>

<pre><code>describes "A really long text that respects the 80-char column marker and
wraps nicely when it exceeds this length."
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I knew that Rails provided a nearly similar method with the name <code>word_wrap</code>,
and I tweaked it a bit to this:</p>

<p>```ruby
class String
  def wrap options = {}</p>

<pre><code>width = options.fetch(:width, 76)
self.strip.split("\n").collect do |line|
  line.length &gt; width ? line.gsub(/(.{1,#{width}})(\s+|$)/, "\\1\n") : line
end.map(&amp;:strip).join("\n")
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  def indent options = {}</p>

<pre><code>spaces = " " * options.fetch(:spaces, 4)
self.gsub(/^/, spaces).gsub(/^\s*$/, '')
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  def indent_with_wrap options = {}</p>

<pre><code>spaces = options.fetch(:spaces, 4)
width  = options.fetch(:width, 80)
width  = width &gt; spaces ? width - spaces : 1
self.wrap(width: width).indent(spaces: spaces)
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>The last method, i.e. <code>indent_with_wrap</code> is what I am interested in, really.
Now, this might not be the best implementation for what I want, but it works and
is self-explanatory to me.</p>

<p>So, now, I can create my ERB template like this to get the desired results:</p>

<p>```ruby
module &lt;%= module_name %>
  class &lt;%= class_name %></p>

<pre><code>&lt;%= "describes #{description}".indent_with_wrap spaces: 4, width: 80 %&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>This makes me a happy panda :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[wish yourself a happy new year]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/wish-yourself-a-happy-new-year/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-01T01:19:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/wish-yourself-a-happy-new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Well, before you do that, I will do it from my side: <code>Happy new year to you!</code></p></blockquote>

<p>So, I was just working on somethings, and found this nice little code snippet
that was totally appropriate for this event.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Ruby</h2>

<p>If you are a fan of the ruby (like me), define a function with the following
definition (try, using <code>irb</code> for this purpose):</p>

<p><code>ruby
def encode(str); str.chars.map(&amp;:ord).inject(:+); end
</code></p>

<p>The above function does the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>accept a string as an input</li>
<li>break it into its constituent characters</li>
<li>convert these characters to their ascii integer value</li>
<li>sum up all the integer values and return that sum</li>
</ul>


<p>Nothin' great about that function, right?<br/>
Now, try this in your <code>irb</code> session:</p>

<p><code>ruby
encode "Happy new year to you!"
</code></p>

<p>You will see that the above function is quite intelligent in itself.</p>

<blockquote><p>That little function is empowered with an artificial intelligence by its code,
without any complex mechanisms :)</p></blockquote>

<p>Oh, and here is an alternative:</p>

<p><code>ruby
Happy = Time
Happy.new.year
</code></p>

<h2>Python</h2>

<p>If you are a python fan, instead, try this:</p>

<p><code>python
encode = lambda str: sum(ord(c) for c in str)
encode("Happy new year to you!")
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Domains on Github Pages without fucking up your Emails]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/custom-domains-on-github-pages-without-fucking-up-your-emails/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-27T16:18:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/custom-domains-on-github-pages-without-fucking-up-your-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As stated in my post titled <a href="/personal/back-with-a-bang/">Back with a Bang!</a>
(that title, still, amuses me), I have moved from
<a href="http://wordpress.org">WordPress</a> to using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> on
Github pages. I was happy with my new blogging configuration, and I think, I am
on schedule with my post updates, till date. However, in making the switch,
I messed up my email configuration while setting up custom domain for this blog.
And, I was not even aware my emails were bouncing off, silently.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The <code>nikhgupta.com</code> domain is registered on <a href="http://namecheap.com">Namecheap</a>
(which has been my reliable domain manager, since the very start), and is hosted
on <a href="http://digitalocean.com">DigitalOcean</a> (which is an amazin' host and my
recommendation, these days). I am using <a href="http://zpanelcp.com">ZPanel</a>, since
cPanel is not a necessity for me (I would, rather, install the bare minimum on
my servers).</p>

<p>I must say that this silent bouncing of my emails was my own idiocy, and
therefore, I am writing this post to help anyone who may have gone through the
same.</p>

<h2>Custom Domain on Github Pages</h2>

<p>This has, already, been discussed on <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-a-custom-domain-with-pages">this Github Help page</a>,
and therefore, I will not go in details. For summary:</p>

<ul>
<li>Create a repository on GitHub with the name of <code>username.github.com</code>.</li>
<li>Next, clone the Octopress (or Jekyll) repository, and make changes, as
required. My source for the website is in <code>source</code> branch, which is pushed to
the same branch on Github, while my website (real HTML pages) are pushed to
the <code>master</code> branch on Github. This is all managed by Octopress, by default.</li>
<li>Once we push the site (or run <code>bundle exec rake gen_deploy</code> if using
Octopress), our site will be viewable at <code>http://username.github.com</code>.</li>
<li>Next, we add a file named <code>CNAME</code> to our <code>source</code> directory. This file is
a simple text file that just contains one line, the domain name you wish to
use. In my case, <code>nikhgupta.com</code>.</li>
<li>Change the DNS settings for your domain to point to GitHub’s servers. Since,
I was using the root domain name, I had to create <code>A</code> records for the <code>@</code> and
<code>www</code> entries, and point them to Github&rsquo;s IP (<code>204.232.175.78</code>).</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ensuring that Email configuration works</h2>

<p>Did you notice that last step? This is where I messed up my email
configuration. The <code>MX</code> records in my DNS settings for this domain, were
pointing to <code>mail.nikhgupta.com</code>, which in turn was pointing to <code>@</code> entry.</p>

<p>Now, that is what is wrong! The <code>@</code> entry was initially pointing to my server&rsquo;s
IP address, which meant that the incoming mails were being processed by my
server.</p>

<p>When I changed the <code>@</code> entry to point to Github&rsquo;s server, I made Github
responsible for managing my mails. Shit! Here is a snapshot for the change,
I made:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/nikhgupta-dns-a-records-digitalocean.png"></p>

<p>Anyways, now, that I am aware of what is wrong, it is a simple fix. I made the
<code>MX</code> records to point to <code>mail.nikhgupta.com</code> (this was the default), but also
made <code>mail</code> A-record to point to my server&rsquo;s IP address (by adding an <code>A</code>
record).</p>

<p>Below are snapshots for my <code>A</code> and <code>MX</code> records, in their current state:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/nikhgupta-dns-a-records.png">
<img class="center" src="/images/nikhgupta-dns-mx-records.png"></p>

<p>Finally, since I am using DigitalOcean server, I also needed to point the same
A-record to the server&rsquo;s IP using the management console provided by
DigitalOcean.</p>

<p>Now, I only had to wait to let the DNS propogate, and my emails were right back
to where they belonged. :)</p>

<p><strong>Update (05.11.2013)</strong>: It seems that I also needed to point out <code>MX</code> record
inside DigitalOcean&rsquo;s DNS settings to <code>mail.nikhgupta.com.</code> to make this all
work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally. A self-hosted Gitlab instance!]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/finally-a-self-hosted-gitlab-instance/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-26T13:26:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/finally-a-self-hosted-gitlab-instance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Alright. I seem to be pretty happy today. I think any stupid developer, like me,
would be in the given circumstances. If you are aware about the existance of
a very nifty witchcraft named <a href="http://github.com">Github</a>, then, I am sure you
will be equally happy for me.</p>

<p><strong>Github is magic</strong>. <em>A protective one.</em></p>

<p>For those unaware, Github is a code hosting platform. It allows me to write my
code and then, keep it safe and versioned in their platform. That way, my code
is always there for me. I can share code with other developers, as well as
<em>fork</em> their work and modify it, locally. And, so on. The cool thing is that the
service is really amazing and free for open-source projects.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, there are times when a person needs some privacy, even with the code,
he writes. Especially, with the code, he writes. I, often, used Github&rsquo;s private
repositories for this purpose. But, with a recent project, I was aiming to
create around 100 different private repositories, which was a bit unmanageable
with Github. I know, I know. I must not need that much private repositories.
But, what can I do about it if the project specification itself demand for the
same.</p>

<p>Therefore, I began looking at private repository hosts, and
<a href="http://bitbucket.org">BitBucket</a> seemed to be off, for some reasons. Finally,
I settled on using <a href="http://gitlab.org">GitlabHQ</a> for my purposes. It offered
everything Github had to offer, and more. More in the sense, that I can host
things privately on my own server. Perfect.</p>

<p>And, since I was already using <a href="http://digitalocean.com">DigitalOcean</a> for
hosting my server, and was using Ubuntu 12.10 as my operating system, it became
really easy to install Gitlab on my server. Followed <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/articles/how-to-set-up-gitlab-as-your-very-own-private-github-clone">this
tutorial</a>
from DigitialOcean&rsquo;s community tutorials, and I was up and running with my own
private repository server.</p>

<p>I was, further, planning to install <a href="http://gitlab.org/gitlab-ci">Gitlab CI</a> on
my server, but that seemed to be an overkill, since I do not think I will need
continuous integration for my private projects, and for public projects, we have
another awesome witchcraft named <a href="http://travis-ci.org">Travis CI</a>.</p>

<p>O'course, you can test drive this on <a href="http://git.wickeddevelopers.com">Git @WickedDevelopers</a>.  <br/>
Happy, code browsing!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
