<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: code | Nikhil Gupta]]></title>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/blog/categories/code/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-27T16:58:51+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nikhgupta.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nikhil Gupta]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@nikhgupta.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[a rubyist's attempt on working with python - setup and first notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/a-rubyists-attempt-on-working-with-python-setup-and-first-notes/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-11T07:42:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/a-rubyists-attempt-on-working-with-python-setup-and-first-notes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I never really needed to look for another language to learn once I was acquinted
with ruby some years back. I love it, and I really do. It provides clean code
which does what it reads &ndash; it feels like the language was written for me, which
was infact the idea behind ruby &ndash; a language made for developers.</p>

<p>But, anyways, I am giving Python another try for with hopes that it will be
fruitful for me to learn the language. It has been, I think, 2-3 years since
I last tried the language for some time, briefly. I have learned a lot in that
duration in the Ruby world. And, I am hoping, if nothing else, this attempt at
Python will make me a better rubyist. This post describes my notes on setting up
a development environment for Python on OSX 10.8 (Mountain Lion), and some
initial learning intakes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Installation</h2>

<p>I preferred not to use the Python distribution that comes with OSX for my dev
needs, which most Pythonista will agree with. The reason is simple &ndash; I do not
want the system based Python to get corrupted while my dev percussions, and is
the same reason why I use <code>rbenv</code> for Ruby development.</p>

<p>So, I looked at some tutorials regarding this, and found that the good old
<code>homebrew</code> that I love has again come up with a rescue. Moreover, it provides me
with <code>pip</code> and <code>setuptools</code>, which is really great.</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<h1>Installs Python 2.x</h1>

<p>brew install python &mdash;with-brewed-openssl</p>

<h1>Links some of the Python Dev. utilities to /Applications directory.</h1>

<p>brew linkapps
```</p>

<p>Alright, so next we need a version control system, for which <code>mercurial</code> is
happily recommended in many tutorials, but I love my VCS and I am not going to
part away from it &ndash; I am loyal to it &ndash; <code>Git</code>.</p>

<p>Finally, lets install <code>virtualenv</code> which creates virtual isolated environments
for our Python projects, kinda like <code>rvm</code> in Ruby world.</p>

<p><code>bash
pip install virtualenv
pip install virtualenvwrapper
</code></p>

<p>Next, I do not want to run <code>pip</code> command against the system python and overwrite
or update a needed library. So, I will tell <code>pip</code> to only instally anything, if
we are in a <code>virtualenv</code> based environment. Add the following two lines to your
<code>~/.bashrc</code>, or <code>zsh</code> configuration file (or, whatever else you use):</p>

<p>```bash
if [[ -s /usr/local/bin/virtualenvwrapper.sh ]]; then</p>

<pre><code>source /usr/local/bin/virtualenvwrapper.sh
</code></pre>

<p>fi</p>

<h1>pip should only run if there is a virtualenv currently activated</h1>

<p>export PIP_REQUIRE_VIRTUALENV=true</p>

<h1>cache pip-installed packages to avoid re-downloading</h1>

<p>export PIP_DOWNLOAD_CACHE=$HOME/.pip/cache</p>

<h1>virtualenv wrapper support</h1>

<p>export WORKON_HOME=~/Code/python/VirtualEnvs</p>

<h1>make pip use the virtualenv dir</h1>

<p>export PIP_VIRTUALENV_BASE=$WORKON_HOME
```</p>

<p>Now, trying to install a package without a valid <code>virtualenv</code> will give an error
that says:</p>

<p><code>bash
~ ➲ pip install markdown
Could not find an activated virtualenv (required).
</code></p>

<p>If you want to use <code>pip</code> for the system based Python, you can add a function
like this in your bash/zsh configuration file:</p>

<p><code>bash
syspip(){
   PIP_REQUIRE_VIRTUALENV="" pip "$@"
}
</code></p>

<p>Create a new virtualenv, using:</p>

<p><code>bash
virtualenv test_project
cd test_project
. bin/activate
</code></p>

<h2>The Editor</h2>

<p>Although, there is a really good <code>PyCharm</code> editor available for Python, I will
still try and stay with my editor of choice: <code>Vim</code>, which is really
magnificient. However, in the upcoming days, I can install and add various
python based features for my vim editor.</p>

<h2>Epilogue</h2>

<p>I have decided to write a separate blog post on what I find inside Python. Will
soon write up about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things you may not know about FactoryGirl]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/rails/things-you-may-not-know-about-factorygirl/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-21T21:57:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/rails/things-you-may-not-know-about-factorygirl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OK, I have been doing a lot (and I mean, a lot) of work on Rails, recently.
I have always loved the simple expressive syntax of Ruby, anyway, so that does
not bother me.</p>

<p>Now, in one of the projects, I have been using <a href="http://github.com/gregbell/active_admin">ActiveAdmin</a>, and
other awesome gems like <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/factory_girl">FactoryGirl</a>, <a href="https://github.com/rspec/rspec-rails">RSpec</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/cucumber/cucumber">Cucumber</a>, etc. And, every now and then, I come across a concept or
feature about these gems that I was not aware about earlier. I wanted to quickly
jot down all these things, in a single place (for future reference). Now, many
of these things might not be new to you, but are to me and are of importance for
me. I am wondering if I should have used a different title for this post, now.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Sequences</h3>

<p>I knew about this feature (obviously). It is simple: if you need an attribute to
change everytime a new factory is built or created &ndash; use a sequence.</p>

<p><code>ruby
sequence(:email) {|n| "email#{n}@factory.com" }
</code></p>

<p>The above sequence will generate different emails each time the factory is
called upon, and thus, helps us in passing validations on unique attributes.</p>

<h3>Dependent Attributes</h3>

<p>This is really cool. The value of one of the attributes can depend upon the
value of another attribute in our factory. Combined with on-the-fly attribute
declaration, we have a really powerful way to create/build factories:</p>

<p><code>ruby
factory :user do
  username "username"
  url { username ? "http://facebook.com/#{username}" : nil }
  verified true
end
</code></p>

<p>Now, when we build the <code>user</code> factory, we get a <code>username</code> and a corresponding
<code>url</code> for our User. But, we can pass a <code>username: nil</code> option to our factory,
and both our <code>username</code> and <code>url</code> fields will be set to <code>nil</code> :)</p>

<p>```ruby
user = FactoryGirl.build :user</p>

<h1>=> #<User id: nil, username: "username", url: "http://facebook.com/username", verified: true></h1>

<p>user = FactoryGirl.build :user, username: nil</p>

<h1>=> #<User id: nil, username: nil, url: nil, verified: true></h1>

<p>user = FactoryGirl.build :user, username: nil, verified: false</p>

<h1>=> #<User id: nil, username: nil, url: nil, verified: false></h1>

<p>```</p>

<h3>Callbacks and Transient Attributes</h3>

<p>We can, even, define some virtual features on our factory. For example, we can
define a <code>with_&lt;feature&gt;</code> transient attribute for our factory, which decides if
a particular feature will be available in our factory or not. For example:</p>

<p>```ruby
factory :user do
  ignore do</p>

<pre><code>with_profile false
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  # &hellip;
  # &hellip;</p>

<p>  after :create do |user, evaluator|</p>

<pre><code>FactoryGirl.create :profile, user: user if evaluator.with_profile
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>This will ensure that a <code>user</code> factory is created with an associated profile
when <code>with_profile: true</code> is passed as an option. Otherwise, a profile for that
user will not be created.</p>

<h3>Traits</h3>

<p>Traits define a group of attributes on the concerned factory which form a part
of a particular behaviour. Now, I never had much use of this particular feature,
but I can see this feature is really really useful.</p>

<p>I won&rsquo;t go into much details of this feature, as it has been described pretty
well in the documentation (yes, I am aware, docs are pretty awesome, and this
post might be really useless).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Filters using Ransacker in ActiveAdmin Interfaces]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/activeadmin/custom-filters-using-ransacker-in-activeadmin-interfaces/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T08:47:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/activeadmin/custom-filters-using-ransacker-in-activeadmin-interfaces</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh, so, you have tried implementing custom filters in your shiny
<a href="active-admin">ActiveAdmin</a> interface, and probably, have already started
despising the time you have wasted in searching for an answer? Yeah, it happened
to me, as well.</p>

<p>Anyways, this post contains my short notes on using <code>ransacker</code> to create
powerful search patterns in my <a href="active-admin">ActiveAdmin</a> interfaces.
Definitely, <code>ransacker</code> is really powerful. You only need to convert the
incoming search filter (e.g. text or ids or anything else) to an equivalent
attribute in the database, and you are done :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Lets, imagine that we have an <a href="active-admin">ActiveAdmin</a> dashboard, with
a <code>User</code> resource. Our app distinguishes users based on some mysterious logic
as: <code>Active Users</code>, <code>Inactive Users</code>, and <code>New Users</code>. Perfect. But, now,
somehow, I need to filter my users as per this categorization (within AA). And,
this is where normal filtering methods stop working for me. Imagine that the
code present in the <code>User</code> model is somewhere along these lines:</p>

<p>```ruby
class User &lt; ActiveRecord::Base</p>

<p>  # categorize a given user as: :new, :active or :inactive
  def categorize</p>

<pre><code># .. mysterious code..
# .. returns one of the symbols: :new, :active or :inactive.
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>end
```</p>

<h3>Step 1: Define the search filter and inputs.</h3>

<p>In order to filter our users based on the above categorization, we first need to
define our filter in AA. This is fairly easy:</p>

<p>```ruby</p>

<h1>app/admin/user.rb</h1>

<p>filter :by_categorization_in, label: &ldquo;Categorization&rdquo;, as: :select, collection: %w[ New Active Inactive ]
```</p>

<p>Yeah, that&rsquo;s it :)</p>

<p>But, the filter will not work, as of now, and if you try to visit your <code>users</code>
resource, it will spit out an error that says (something like):</p>

<p><code>ruby
undefined method `by_categorization_in' for #&lt;Ransack::Search:0x007fe2365288a0&gt;'`
</code></p>

<p>Obviously, we are yet to define how the filtering will take place.</p>

<h3>Step 2: Define the filtering method, a.k.a. ransacker</h3>

<p>Alright, so the error says that the given filtering method could not be found,
and therefore, we will start with its implementation. <a href="ransack">Ransack</a> is the
search library used by AA, and it provides a <code>ransacker</code> method that we can use
in our models to define custom search methods. Since, we defined our filter as
<code>by_categorization_in</code>, our ransacker method should be named as: <code>by_categorization</code>:</p>

<p>```ruby</p>

<h1>app/models/user.rb</h1>

<p>class User &lt; ActiveRecord::Base</p>

<p>  # categorize a given user as: :new, :active or :inactive
  def categorize</p>

<pre><code># .. mysterious code..
# .. returns one of the symbols: :new, :active or :inactive.
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  # define our custom search method
  ransacker :by_categorization, proc{ |v|</p>

<pre><code># some code..
</code></pre>

<p>  } do |parent|</p>

<pre><code># some other code..
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<h3>Step 3: Define our filtering algorithm</h3>

<p>So, finally, we define how the filter will actually work. This is fairly easy
step, as well. Notice the <code>proc</code> in the <code>ransacker</code> method above? Also, the
<code>parent</code> variable? Yeah, we need to use them to define which users will be
filtered and which will be displayed.</p>

<p>In the given <code>proc</code>, the variable <code>v</code> is nothing special, and simply, contains
the search term we are filtering upon. In our case, this will be one of the
<code>New</code>, <code>Active</code> or <code>Inactive</code> words. The purpose of the <code>proc</code> being to map this
variable to an equivalent attribute in the user&rsquo;s table. Therefore, we can do
something like:</p>

<p>```ruby</p>

<h1>app/models/user.rb</h1>

<p>class User &lt; ActiveRecord::Base</p>

<p>  # categorize a given user as: :new, :active or :inactive
  def categorize</p>

<pre><code># .. mysterious code..
# .. returns one of the symbols: :new, :active or :inactive.
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  # a class method that returns the users belonging to a given category.
  def self.in_category(category = :new)</p>

<pre><code># .. could have been some really mysterious code, again..
# .. but, then, I am nobody :( ..
all.select{|user| user.categorize == category.to_s.underscore.to_sym }
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  # define our custom search method
  ransacker :by_categorization, proc{ |v|</p>

<pre><code>data = User.in_category(v).map(&amp;:id)
data = data.present? ? data : nil
</code></pre>

<p>  } do |parent|</p>

<pre><code># some other code..
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
<code>``
I know that the above way to find out which user ids belong to a particular
category is really inefficient, but this is an example. Alright, so we made the
</code>proc` return some user IDs belonging to the category we were interested in.</p>

<p>Next is the <code>parent</code> variable, which probably is some weird ruby object, and to
be honest I am not entirely sure what all capabilities it provides (though, it
seems that I can use associations, fetch records for the given model, etc. using
this object). But, what we are really interested is in the <code>parent.table</code>
variable, which is an instance of the <code>Arel::Table</code> class, representing our
<code>users</code> table in the database. The purpose of this block is to obtain an
attribute from this table (a.k.a., an <code>Arel::Attributes::Attribute</code>), and match
the values returned by the <code>proc</code> above with the values for this attribute
across the whole <code>users</code> table. Values returned from the <code>proc</code> matching the
given attribute for any record in the database table (i.e. our <code>users</code> table)
will be returned and the rest entries/users will be filtered.</p>

<p>```ruby</p>

<h1>app/models/user.rb</h1>

<p>class User &lt; ActiveRecord::Base</p>

<p>  # categorize a given user as: :new, :active or :inactive
  def categorize</p>

<pre><code># .. mysterious code..
# .. returns one of the symbols: :new, :active or :inactive.
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  # a class method that returns the users belonging to a given category.
  def self.in_category(category = :new)</p>

<pre><code># .. could have been some really mysterious code, again..
# .. but, then, I am nobody :( ..
all.select{|user| user.categorize == category.to_s.underscore.to_sym }
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  # define our custom search method
  ransacker :by_categorization, proc{ |v|</p>

<pre><code>data = User.in_category(v).map(&amp;:id)
data = data.present? ? data : nil
</code></pre>

<p>  } do |parent|</p>

<pre><code>parent.table[:id]
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>Done! The above should provide us with everything that we need to filter out our
users based on their categorization. Happy ransacking :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[serving legacy php applications using Apache alongside Pow]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/serving-legacy-php-applications-using-apache-alongside-pow/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-03T06:49:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/serving-legacy-php-applications-using-apache-alongside-pow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have started using <a href="http://pow.cx">Pow</a> lately, which I have avoided for
a long time, without any explicit reasoning. Now that I have actually tried it,
I can definitely say that using Pow is really a breeze, and is really powerful
at the same time. Before this, I used to run Phusion Passenger for my needs, and
while that was a lot more powerful, it was a lot more fuss for my naive needs.</p>

<p>Now, Pow is really great for Rack based applications, but does not work well
enough with other applications, e.g. the ones using PHP. What makes it worse is
that the default Pow configuration takes over the port 80, and thereby, my
Apache server will never be hit. Great.</p>

<p>I, quickly, googled some stuff and found a way to make Apache and Pow play
nicely with each other, and at the same time remove the need for <code>dnsmasq</code>,
which I am, currently, using to resolve arbitrary top-level domains. This post
contains my notes on this topic.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Uninstall Pow</h2>

<p>The first step we need to perform is to uninstall Pow, if it is already
installed. That way, we make sure that nothing interferes with our setup.</p>

<p><code>bash
curl get.pow.cx/uninstall.sh | sh
</code></p>

<h2>Add Configuration for Pow</h2>

<p>We will tell Pow to use the port 3100, instead of taking over port 80, and let
the poor Apache be. Furthermore, I will tell Pow to resolve a number of TLDs to
<code>127.0.0.1</code>.</p>

<p><code>bash
echo 'export POW_DST_PORT=88' &gt;&gt; ~/.powconfig
echo 'export POW_DOMAINS=dev,pow,lab,test' &gt;&gt; ~/.powconfig
</code></p>

<p>From the above list of TLDs, we want <code>dev</code>, and <code>pow</code> to serve applications
using Pow, while <code>lab</code> and <code>test</code> will be serving Apache based applications
using VirtualHost directives.</p>

<h2>Adding Apache VirtualHosts</h2>

<p>First, we will tell Apache to pass any requests for <code>dev</code>, and <code>pow</code> TLDs to
Pow using reverse proxy:</p>

<p>```apache
<VirtualHost *:80></p>

<pre><code>ServerName pow
ServerAlias *.dev *.pow *.xip.io

ProxyPass / http://localhost:20559/
ProxyPassReverse / http://localhost:20559/
ProxyPreserveHost On
</code></pre>

<p></VirtualHost>
```</p>

<p>Having done that, we tell Apache to serve up the remaining TLDs from
a particular directory:</p>

<p>```apache
<VirtualHost *:80></p>

<pre><code>ServerName lab
ServerAlias *.lab *.test
VirtualDocumentRoot "/Users/nikhgupta/Code/legacy-apps/%1"
</code></pre>

<p></VirtualHost>
```</p>

<p>Now, make sure that the above directives are being served up by Apache by
including them in your <code>httpd.conf</code> somewhere, somehow.</p>

<h2>Restart Apache</h2>

<p>Apache will use the above VirtualHost directives upon restart/reload:</p>

<p><code>bash
sudo apachectl restart
</code></p>

<h2>Install Pow</h2>

<p>All that remains is to install Pow:</p>

<p><code>bash
curl get.pow.cx | sh
</code></p>

<h2>Install Powder</h2>

<p>Oh, yes, this is my favorite. Simply, install Powder to further simplify your
life.</p>

<p><code>bash
gem install powder
</code></p>

<p><em>Ecstatic</em> :)</p>

<h2>Results?</h2>

<p>For starters, I can serve up any rack based application by simply running
<code>powder list</code> in that directory, and then access it using <code>appname.dev</code> or
<code>appname.pow</code>. And, this also works for static websites as well e.g.
<a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> (note that, this requires that the current
directory has a <code>public</code> sub directory which contains an <code>index.html</code> file.)</p>

<p>Moreover, my old Apache configurations run without any implications. And,
therefore, I can keep on working on applications that are served using PHP.</p>

<p>Effectively, I can run a ruby/rails based application in a single step by
running <code>powder link</code>, and a php application in zero steps by simply placing it
at the correct location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[wrapping long lines in ruby for display in source files]]></title>
    <link href="http://nikhgupta.com/code/wrapping-long-lines-in-ruby-for-display-in-source-files/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T02:42:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nikhgupta.com/code/wrapping-long-lines-in-ruby-for-display-in-source-files</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While working on a gem, I needed to generate ruby classes on the fly. Yeah,
I know this should never be the case, unless I needed around 600+ classes (I was
converting schema.org schemas to ruby classes).</p>

<p>Now, this required me to add descriptive text inside these classes, but the text
was very long and I hated how the text overflowed the screen. I use vim, which
promptly highlights the 80-char column marker on my source files, and I wanted
this text to stick to that. Effectively, I wanted something like the following:</p>

<p>```ruby
module MyModule
  class MyClass</p>

<pre><code>describes "A really long text that respects the 80-char column marker and
wraps nicely when it exceeds this length."
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I knew that Rails provided a nearly similar method with the name <code>word_wrap</code>,
and I tweaked it a bit to this:</p>

<p>```ruby
class String
  def wrap options = {}</p>

<pre><code>width = options.fetch(:width, 76)
self.strip.split("\n").collect do |line|
  line.length &gt; width ? line.gsub(/(.{1,#{width}})(\s+|$)/, "\\1\n") : line
end.map(&amp;:strip).join("\n")
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  def indent options = {}</p>

<pre><code>spaces = " " * options.fetch(:spaces, 4)
self.gsub(/^/, spaces).gsub(/^\s*$/, '')
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  def indent_with_wrap options = {}</p>

<pre><code>spaces = options.fetch(:spaces, 4)
width  = options.fetch(:width, 80)
width  = width &gt; spaces ? width - spaces : 1
self.wrap(width: width).indent(spaces: spaces)
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>The last method, i.e. <code>indent_with_wrap</code> is what I am interested in, really.
Now, this might not be the best implementation for what I want, but it works and
is self-explanatory to me.</p>

<p>So, now, I can create my ERB template like this to get the desired results:</p>

<p>```ruby
module &lt;%= module_name %>
  class &lt;%= class_name %></p>

<pre><code>&lt;%= "describes #{description}".indent_with_wrap spaces: 4, width: 80 %&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>This makes me a happy panda :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
